ERIC BUDD

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

eric.b.budd@gmail.com

(816) 812 - 0565 References available upon request.

Profile

An experienced developer with a broad background and the ability to deliver, focused on object-oriented design, data modeling, and agile processes.

Skills

Web Programming

Taking advantage of Ruby and Rails to build clean, powerful, and maintainable code.

Data Modeling

Understanding business data and relational systems to build safe, efficient databases.

Agile Development

Using modern development techniques to ensure code quality, correctness, and timeliness.

Experience

Strenuus

Software Engineer

Strenuus is the largest collector of managed health care data in the US.

April 2015 - Present

- Part of the team that developed and deployed Provider Nexus, a RESTful JSON API for exposing health provider, location, and insurance plan data to consumer interfaces.
- · Performed deep query and code optimization in all areas of the API system.
- Helped develop import processes to generate gigabytes of deeply structured data on a nightly basis.
- · Assisted in ongoing Ruby on Rails development efforts, using React, Redux, and Flux.

UnitedLex

Software Engineer

UnitedLex is a global leader in legal and data solutions

- · Built out service layer, exposing RESTful API for other apps' consumption
- · Assisted in the architecture and development of a work distribution engine.
- · Used Knockout.js to build and modify UI
- · Developed suite of unit tests to verify system functionality
- · Various refactoring, configuration and documentation tasks

readMedia, Inc./Merit Pages, Inc. Software Engineer

June 2012 - August 2014

August 2014 - April 2015

readMedia helps its customers get attention for their schools, for their students, and for themselves.

- · Maintained and implemented new features in existing legacy software
- Assisted in development and debugging of new MeritPages.com product
- · Assisted in creation of SOA for primary products
- · Developed data warehouse for ad-hoc and customer reporting and graphing
- · Implemented code quality thresholds, unit testing, and architecture reviews
- · Provided maintenance and support for all aspects of the application

Google (via acquisition) Software Engineer

September 2011 - June 2012

Google's mission is to organize the world's information and make it universally accessible and useful.

- Implemented Google's Kennedy theming and branding in Zavers' El Paso Proxy Authentication Server.
- Overhauled El Paso branding and flow to integrate with Google services and retailers.
- Added flows and branding for Winn-Dixie and D'Agostino's retailers
- Participated in redeveloping cross-team workflows for development and deployment of Zavers' back-end services
- · Developed retailer-specific mobile coupon site
- · Implemented SSO authentication integration solution for retailers

Zavers.com (acquired by Google) Software Engineer

April 2008 - September 2011

Zavers.com provides a digital coupon platform, integrated at the point of sale, serving the needs of consumers, retailers, and manufacturers.

- · Translated business requirements into features and stories.
- · Participated in the architecture, design, and implementation of a prototype service in Ruby on Rails.
- Built and maintained a thorough test suite with RSpec, Selenium, Test::Unit and Webrat.
- Assisted in the architecture and development of a scalable SOA implementation with Rails, Sinatra, and Rack.
- · Assisted in the development of Capistrano scripts to ease deployment.
- · Developed internal tools for testing, monitoring, data generation, and load testing.
- Throroughly documented public and private APIs and tools.

BensonsLife.com (Freelance)

March 2009 - January 2012

Software Engineer/Contract

BensonsLife.com is a social networking site with a focus on privacy, security, and local communities and groups.

- Translated business requirements into stories and features.
- Architected and implemented business requirements in Ruby on Rails.
- · Wrote and maintained a thorough test suite with RSpec and Story Runner.
- · Configured and maintained VPSes for all services.
- · Configured and maintained all services, including nginx, Subversion, Postfix, and MySQL.
- Wrote and maintained scripts for deploying application code with Capistrano.
- · Performed occasional emergency troubleshooting.

Grantham Education Corporation

July 2006 - April 2008

Programming Manager/Senior Programmer (promoted)

Grantham University is a nationally-accredited online university providing bachelor's and master's degrees, with a focus on deployed military and nontraditional students.

- · Implemented and maintained new system architecture for core business application.
- · Managed staff of six developers.
- Developed timelines and project plans for development staff to meet organizational goals.
- Translated business objectives into code requirements.
- · Responsible for reporting progress and issues to the business, and for maintaining code and data quality.
- · Developed modules to consume APIs and services via SOAP, XML-RPC, REST, FTP and others.
- · Led optimization and deployment efforts.

Programmer Analyst

July 2005 - July 2006

- · Implemented Subversion and Trac for versioning and bug tracking to replace shares and spreadsheets.
- Completed and deployed abandoned core business application, written in C#/.Net.
- · Maintained and updated student-facing website, written in classic ASP/VBScript.
- · Re-architected core application from the ground up to correct schema, architecture, and code quality.
- · Implemented new architecture as a Rails web service, exposing business logic through an XML-RPC API.
- Assisted with moving services and recovering data in the wake of severe business disruption due to Hurricane Katrina.
- Assisted networking/hardware team with maintaining and updating servers, including emergency response, tool evaluation, and penetration analysis.

SCP Pool Corp./Ascent Consulting Software Engineer

January 2004 - September 2004

SCP Pool Corp. is the world's largest wholesale distributor of swimming pool supplies.

- Developed, maintained, and supported processes to move data on a nightly basis from the legacy Pick systems to an SQL data warehouse environment and customer systems.
- · Managed and administered the transfer of scheduled jobs from PHANTOM to the cron scheduler.
- · Maintained and developed reports from the legacy systems and the data warehouse.
- · Helped develop back-end validation components for the Web-based E-Commerce system.
- Analyzed and documented the legacy segmented sequential access data files and developed C++ software
 to retrieve checksums from the data files directly, rather than using the TCL interface.

Turning Point Solutions Group

June 2000 - December 2003

Programmer/System Administrator

 $Turning\ Point\ Solutions\ Group\ provides\ complete\ network\ and\ custom\ software\ solutions\ for\ businesses,\ organizations\ and\ individuals.$

- Designed and developed desktop and web applications with C#, Visual Basic 6, Classic ASP, PHP,
 Microsoft Access, MySQL, and SQL Server:
- Medical: transcription tracking and reporting, pharmaceutical dispensation and tracking, medical device sales tracking, and serial robotics communication.
- · Churches: web content development and automation.
- Manufacturing: Automated EDS transactions.
- State and Local Government: Social service reporting and job training and education sites.
- Performed data conversion services for SQL Server (7.0 and 2000), MySQL 3.X, and Microsoft Access from Oracle, Pervasive SQL, Clipper, RPG2, and numerous minor proprietary formats.
- · Installed, secured, administered, and maintained web hosting and DNS servers on Windows and Linux

UniComp, Inc.

May 1998 - June 2000

Database Developer/Programmer

 $\label{thm:comp} \mbox{UniComp, Inc. provided database and application development services for small-to-medium businesses.}$

- Designed and developed database applications for MS-DOS, Windows 9X and SCO Unix platforms using
 a variety of tools, including Informix-SQL, C, Visual Basic, and Microsoft Access.
- Developed software and databases for a variety of industries, including hospitality, retail, trucking, and hospice care.
- Developed hand-held data collection for ruggedized Telxon and Radix devices in C and Assembly.
- Developed remote floodgate control with Visual Basic communicating to hardware relays.
- · Provided technical documentation and on-site training for end-users and developers.

Open Source Projects & Contributions Ctrl-C.club http://ctrl-c.club

Ctrl-C Club is a Linux server offering free SSH and web accounts to users who want to build webpages, chat online, learn Linux, play text console games, or practice writing software.

· Owner and primary administrator

Elixir

http://elixir-lang.org/

A dynamic, functional language designed for building scalable and maintainable applications.

· Improved ANSI color handling

Spree

http://spreecommerce.com/

An open source online commerce solution built with Ruby on Rails

· Added inventory features and layout changes

Grep-Fu gem

https://github.com/Calamitous/grep-fu/tree/master

A very fast, Rails-oriented command-line helper script for grep

· Primary developer

PDF-Writer library

http://ruby-pdf.rubyforge.org/pdf-writer

A library for creating PDF documents using only native Ruby libraries

• Contributed formatting feature and minor bugfixes

Mustard Gas (HN3)

https://github.com/Calamitous/MustardGas

A Google Chrome extension for displaying the top 3 news items from Hacker News (http://news.ycombinator.com)

· Primary developer

BucketWise

https://github.com/jamis/bucketwise

A web-based personal finance manager with a focus on non-OCD budgeting and avoiding credit card debt

· Minor configuration and resource handling corrections (not upstreamed)

Chicken Little

https://github.com/Calamitous/chicken little

A remote web server monitoring script written in Ruby

· Primary developer

Tinderbox

http://rubyforge.org/projects/tinderbox

A Gnome GUI for Campfire chat (http://www.campfirenow.com)

· Primary developer

Bouken

https://github.com/Calamitous/bouken

A simple branching path game engine in Ruby

· Primary developer

Education

University of Southwestern Louisiana Computer Science, Business Track

Attended Summer 1993, Fall 1996 to Fall 1998

Louisiana College English and Computer Science

Attended Summer 1991, Fall 1992 to Spring 1996

Technical Keywords

Ruby	Ruby on Rails	C#
RSpec	Test::Unit	Webrat
JQuery	Prototype	AJAX
Agile/XP	Remote Working	Pair Programming
OOP	SOA	TDD/BDD
Git	Subversion	SQL
MySQL	MS SQL Server	Vim
Linux	OS X	Windows
API/Systems Documentation	DocBook	Markdown
REST	XML-RPC	AWS
S ₃	EC2	Node.js
Knockout.js	Async	Sinon
Istanbul	Mocha	Knottie
Postgresql	JSON	

Eric Budd — 11303 NW 60th St., Parkville, MO 64152 — (816) 812 - 0565 — eric.b.budd@gmail.com